give everything away or give your money
away and buy products you're now saving
your money so that you can buy to so you
can invest in your business yeah you're
going to buy things but it's going to be
things that are useful that is needed
right
and um I think on the entrepreneurial
side you're more cautious on how you
spend your money because you know that
cash flow is so important because if you
don't have cash flow you can't do
anything your business can fall apart um
if if we want to sustain a uh if you
want to be a successful business person
you have to be able to know how to like
it's it's okay to buy what you need to
buy like if you want a home theater buy
it do what you got to do but don't put
your life at risk over those products
and services okay entrepreneurship let's
let's just go down into like action
stuff um flat screen TV new one like
what can we spend for it let's just take
a mid-range model that's probably like
$1,500 um about that let's just take
let's just take take that so 50 and
we're live welcome to the hustle Zone
this is Rip res AKA RP to God AKA The
Wizard because I make stuff happen I'm
going to make it you know that I don't
swear like sometimes I get caught off
guard um today we have a special guest
and we're going to be doing Reg regular
segment with the hustle Zone um as much
times as I can get get this guy to come
on uh we're going to call this this
segment or this this this type of show
uh called Inside the entrepreneur's Mind
um where we kind of
explore how we'll take things that we
see in current events and we'll
explore what those things how how those
events um play in our mind and what when
we see certain things happen like what
does it to us special guest um you've
seen him before in the hustle Zone uh he
has developed his own method of
psychology uh this he's brilliant man
he's so talented in so many different
ways he's a martial artist uh he is uh
he is an artist he's a photographer all
kinds of things that he does um he you
know he's he's mentored he's given
advice to celebrities uh so you know I I
don't like to waste this guy's time so
I'm just going to get right into it guys
welcome Patrick Vanderbilt right so I I
don't know I let's play I'm going to
play a clip of
2016 yeah so we're going to just talk in
the the background here so as you can
see I just see guys
fighting
um over what like I don't even see a
product in their hand and then what it
looks like here it either looks like
people are looting or they're just just
grabbing toilet paper I mean
like is it that necessary
to I guess it was a really good deal on
toilet paper man
yeah I I honestly I would fight over
Charmaine you know like Charmaine is
such a good
[Laughter]
brand I'll elbow someone for some
Charmaine if there's the only one left
but um yeah look at this this is insane
like what creates this Mass hysteria
like what what drives people to to go
through
this um or what they perceive to be a
good
deal exactly because that's the other
part you know I mean we talked about it
a little bit before the show that um
nowadays A lot of times that the
perception of Black Friday having good
deals and
the thing marketed the right way when
people have the perception of getting a
good deal that's sometimes enough it
doesn't even have to be objectively a
good deal um just the behaviors you know
like we can we can say that the the
Pinnacle of American society or you know
North American society living in a
democracy is freedom of
choice M and being able to choose
whatever you want to do be able to live
like your king or queen right we have
that we don't live in a communist uh
government or Society where there's
author authorative government that
controls what you you can do how much
money you can make Etc we don't live in
a monarchy we don't have K we don't have
to um we don't have a king or queen um
we just what we have is
choice and the choices that to like we
we have the ability to live in a free
free Society where we could buy whatever
we want uh so what's wrong with
consumerism then I think that like
there's nothing wrong with it I just
think that people when they try to ask
themselves why am I not rich why am I
not wealthy why don't I have the things
that I want well I think it's because of
things like Black Friday I think that
consumerism really drives that that
narrative that you know if you buy all
the time you're not going to have if
you're not really focusing your time in
investing and and and and strategic Ally
using your money in different ways you
know if you're not doing that stuff then
you're not going to
succeed yeah I mean it boils down to
what I always call narratives you know
which narratives do you believe and
which ones are you exposed to sometimes
um you know uh if if we for example look
at and we entrepreneurs or we marketers
are are partially um guilty of creating
a little bit of that because of course
course most of us want somebody else to
believe your life's going to be better
if you buy my product um and that's
that's a very prevalent narrative in the
world you know um your kids are going to
be happier and not always ask you know
are we there yet if you have this new
car or um I don't know your your health
is going to be better if you drink this
new drink and um if you have this new
pill and your muscles are going to grow
faster if uh you buy this workout
product um and and we're very good as
marketers at giving people a reason to
believe that not only just telling the
story but giving them quote unquote a
good reason to believe that mhm and a
part of if we go if we now scale up you
know or if we chunk up so to say like
they say in NLP and if we look at it
from um from a higher
perspective then the narrative is you
know if you have a lot of stuff your
life is going to be better if you have
the bigger house you're going to be
happier if you have the big car people
are going to like you
more it's it's really always going back
to the very basic human needs and that's
what the story is that sort that comes
through um consumerism you know
consumerism always tells you you need
this this and that in order to be happy
mhm and
um and even though there is a part that
makes us happy that happiness is
temporary mhm if you don't have
something bigger and that's what we
really get into the meat of
Entrepreneurship of the real
entrepreneurs
that do it because they really want to
contribute something you know then we're
getting into the deep stuff and then
we're getting into the stuff that
actually makes entrepreneurs that drives
them that keeps them driving forward
that keeps them happy and fulfilled and
content um and that will change your
life as an entrepre entrepreneur from
everybody else's life as an entrepreneur
while everybody else is hustling and
grinding and in in a way where it's uh
it's painful for them and I'm not saying
like you can't avoid all
pain but if you have meaning if you have
a why and if your why is more than I
want to buy that Lamborghini or I want
to have that uh 10 bedroom
house that everything changes at that
point in time and unfortunately and then
when when you're off work what are you
doing for those four hours well you go
and
Shop right you do something that makes
you feel good yeah or that somebody
tells you that will make you feel good
um yeah but I mean it's like again it's
all about stories right so um one thing
with uh people going into a job of
obviously is that number one they're
just used to it you know it's still one
of the main stories and it's kind of
slowly starting to die out because
people notice that the security that
they used to have in a job is an
illusion and it doesn't exist anymore
like that's gone you can lose your job
tomorrow um the other thing through the
internet for example that people start
to figure out is why should I go and
work in uh work for somebody else create
for somebody else eight hours a day or
more
when I could use that same time and my
talents to create my
own Empire so to say or create something
for myself that will last me much longer
um so now what is happening is the
scales are kind of tipping the Fear
Factor of being employed and losing your
job is now bigger for some people than
the Fear Factor of um um of going into
entrepreneurialism or and starting their
own
thing especially because the stories
that we can now be exposed to if you go
into the right nooks and crannies of the
internet now you can be exposed to the
story I've done it I'm not clever and
I've been successful so if I can do it
you can do it and here are a couple of
ways how to do it you know um we have to
to consider that people like Napoleon
Hill not everybody was exposed to
Napoleon Hill you were exposed to
Napoleon Hill if somebody else read his
book and told you about it mhm and the
normal worker most of the time didn't
read the book you know um it's like it
was very difficult for normal joeo to
come across the knowledge that told them
that they can do this too and nowadays
with the internet it is way easier to
just by accident some times come across
the Gary vayer truck which for some
people as a as a starting point might
not be bad you know um or a lot of other
people that are out there that's why you
know we're we're constantly we're like
you know there's there's like
consumerism just amplifies a lot of
things like
eating like the the fact that we need to
eat so much food to the point where we
can't walk anymore
you know and we're living unhealthy uh
Lifestyles that are unnatural you know
though we have the choice to eat as much
as we want um it does have um implicit
costs to not only to ourselves but to
our families and um so we have we have
obesity we have the influx of
crime uh we have
uh we have just over uh we we have
pollution you know and and there's
global warming whether people like to
believe it or not I I do believe that
you know some of some effects of of of
some of the things that we do some of
the factories that we have does have
some effect to our um to to our society
it does have an effect on our our on our
water system on
wildlife in the the the toxins that are
are are being emitted into the air I do
believe that like you know I I think
it's hard not to believe that there
there are like I mean I lean right in
terms of my belief systems but I'm not
oblivious to pollution and I think
that's all stem from the consumerism
right um it's very inconvenient to be an
entrepreneur there is a lot of sacrifice
that an entrepreneur has to um just deal
with especially in the beginning you
know um I always teach my students
success is
sacrifice the measure of success that
you want to have uh will be dependent on
how much you're willing to
sacrifice and it's just completely
related to that and if you look at at
Steve Jobs you know I mean Steve
Jobs um how much time did the guy really
have with his family and friends you
know where you could just relax and be
Steve I think entrepreneurs nowadays
have a very unique opportunity they have
the opportunity to actually create
businesses that take Humanity back into
the
equation you know clothing companies
that produce clothing where people down
the line are paid
well and and where you know it's just
like the quality is better it's better
for the planet actually like make a
little bit of a difference um if we want
to if we're willing to give up
convenience for a little bit so
consumerism to me always has an
intricate connection with con uh
convenience right and you know I I think
that um and we're always going to have
that balance we're always going to be
trying to figure this out and try like
you know and like I think there are
people at times that are trying to solve
try to make things so that people are
not
overindulging um and but at the same
same time being able to ex like you know
to uh use their freedoms to do whatever
they want to do and as an entrepreneur
why I asked that question earlier is
because I like when you become an
entrepreneur it's almost like the tables
turn it flips instead of you being
wanting to give everything away or give
your money away and buy products you're
now saving your money so that you can
buy to so you can invest in your
business yeah you're going to buy things
but it's going to be things that are
useful that is needed right
and um I think on the entrepreneurial
side you're more cautious on how you
spend your money because you know that
cash flow is so important because if you
don't have cash flow you can't do
anything your business can fall apart uh
if if we want to sustain a uh if you
want to be a successful business person
you have to be able to know how to like
it's it's okay to buy what you need to
buy like if you want a home theater buy
it do what you got to do but don't put
your life at risk over those products
and services okay entrepreneurship let's
let's just go down into like action
stuff um flat screen TV new one like
what can we spend for it let's just take
a mid-range model that's probably like
$1500 um about that let's just take
let's just take take that
so
$1,500 do you know how
much on Facebook advertising you could
spend on a campaign to boost your
business or to sell your
products um or to do anything else with
that that actually then multiplies your
money like a lot of people don't think
about that that that is the difference
you know a lot of people there are a lot
of people that became Rich because when
they made a lot of money in the
beginning of their business they didn't
go out and buy the Lamborghini or the
Porsche in the beginning um they went
out and took that money and put it into
their
business to grow their business that
could be because you know you spend it
on an additional assistant or on an
additional salesperson or it could be
advertising um it could be anything but
but they knew that if I put this money
back into my business it's going to
multiply I I'm a I'm a fan of Warren
Buffett you know I love Warren Buffett
strategy Benjamin Graham that book um
the intelligent investor and and being
being able to realize like for me
investing in stocks and bonds Etc has
always been you know a mystery to me
right and um and rightly so because you
can't predict the future you don't know
what's going to happen when you invest
in the company you don't know what's
going to happen with your money um and a
lot of people are afraid of that a lot
of people are afraid of making those
choices however Warren Buffett his point
of view in investing was that not to
gamble at all not to speculate you know
enter into
businesses that you understand that you
know and you know just invest in
something that you really like that you
know that's not going to you know cuz he
he uses this famous example of
bubblegum saying that we're always going
to be chewing gun any way like we're
talking about consumerism I think that
people react to like the point I'm
trying to make is that people are not
really thinking about how they're
spending the money and they're they're
reacting
to internal external stimuli instead of
their their own internal strategy
and I think as entrepreneurs we are more
strategic in how we spend our money
where we
think you know we're we're constantly
thinking of ways that we can grow our
funds and it's independent of what's
happening around us sometimes there are
things that we respond to because a lot
of people respond to when the stock is
going up oh let's buy let's buy let's
buy for me I respond when it's going
down you know when everybody else is not
looking at something I look at something
that has value and I invest in it when
it's when no one's really paying
attention to
it you know and by reading Rich Dad Poor
Dad by reading the intelligent investor
even Napoleon H Hill to a certain extent
you can you'll have a better like you'll
you'll be more you I think you'll think
more
rationally when dealing with your
finances and when we think rational
thinking rational thinking is just
knowing your options and I don't think
that we're really exploring our options
as much we're just being consumed by
what we see on TV what we read in
magazines Etc but we're not really um
exploring the options within ourselves
on what we can do to better Our Lives
well here is one of the the biggest
problems that a lot of people have um
it's that they
think what they know is all there is to
know what they think they know is all
there is to know and there's nothing
else to know and the truth is that um
that the
biggest the biggest insights and what
can Propel you forward as an individual
as an entrepreneur as a business lies in
the unknown in in the parts that you
don't even know that you don't
know and when you have that mindset of
there is is still so much more out to
learn and Beyond the next Corner might
be something that will explain to me how
I can make more money how I can be
happier and if I keep on searching for
that then I will find it because now my
mind I'm telling my mind go and look for
this and if I just detect a slight
slight piece of that somewhere then my
mind is going to recognize it but it
will only do that if I say what I know
right now is only a very very minute
small tiny fraction of what there is to
know um you know and it's it's like that
knowledge is out there if you look for
it you will find it especially nowadays
in the in the days of the internet I
mean there is so much information out
there if you if you spend some time on
it if you go and really research deep
don't just go with the first few you
know pages that you get on Google don't
just go with Wikipedia you know like if
anything Wikipedia for example sometimes
is is not a bad starting point but what
you should do is you should go down and
look at the external sources and then
that's your real starting point where
you can do more research and that's then
where it branches off more and more and
the deeper you dig and the more you
follow the more you will find out and a
lot of people don't have that stamina so
it's like nowadays there's too much
emotion there's too much uh the idea
that um I should have it
now um and there's too little of that
idea of let me work for it let me look
for it if I don't understand this right
now there is a solution and there is a
way for me to understand so if I just
keep on looking and looking and looking
I will find the information and that
information is going to lift me to the
next level and you know and from a like
a spiritual standpoint and you know when
you talk about the secret you talk about
um The Law of Attraction and I I
honestly Patrick whether I don't know if
you believe in that stuff or you don't
um I'm not a firm believer in the Law of
Attraction I'm not I really don't really
like that concept because it's quite
misleading the concept is
misunderstood and um I I'm a firm
believer that you know if you but if you
do focus on material things and material
gratification you only get as far as a
like you know on a spiritual perspective
it doesn't do well for you um internally
you know it's it's just it it g it gives
you it's it just messes with your
emotions and um and people don't really
make really good decisions when they are
in distress or when they are in in in a
demand for something that they really
shouldn't have you know do you know what
the one thing that you said I I I
thought was really important uh that's
why I just kind of jumped in here yeah
go ahead go ahead um if you keep
focusing
outward your internal happiness is going
to
lack and it's going to lag behind
actually if you keep focusing outward
and looking at what you can do outside
of you to make yourself happier and what
you can have others do or what you can
get that makes you
happier your focus is not enough inside
and if your focus is outward and not
inward at all then happiness is going to
escape you every single time and it's
going to keep escaping you because
you're going to be happy for a moment
you're going to get that jolt of being
really happy when you get make that next
purchase but then it's going to
disappear again because we get used to
stuff but if you figure out how to have
the happiness in here and in here um and
if you work on that happiness with other
people then that will just become
stronger you know
budget you know start there like Black
Friday should not matter to you if you
budget you know if if or if it does then
it's you know there's a reason you know
you'll have a better why to why you
would engage in that activity so that
you have at least the budget will is
never it's not used to be something that
is set in stone it's used to be a guide
and it guides your decisions and it
helps you to make better decisions and
with every
plan there is an opportunity to learn
learning is planning planning is
learning so it allows you to do research
it allows you to figure things out and
it makes you more confident when you're
out there spending
money you know cuz if you don't have a
budget you don't have a guide you don't
have a frame of reference and you don't
know what what is available out there
and if you guys want us to co coach you
or help you or give you some advice hit
us
up hit us up let's talk about it let's
get to the next level and let's learn
together or if you guys have some advice
you want to come on to the hpal Zone and
share that come aboard like let's make
let's take this to the next level you
know so that that's my actionable item
uh and I'll uh we'll end with uh
Patrick Yeah I will always say to people
um what you know right now is not all
there is to know and if you have a goal
and you have not achieved the goal yet
then there is still something that you
have to learn go out and learn it go go
out and find the
information um and start
questioning what is going on around you
what people are doing especially people
who are not at the place where you want
to be seek out the people that already
have want the path information that's
why Ryan said you know like you guys can
write us a message and if you have a
question you know send us a question who
knows maybe we're going to get you on
the next hustle Zone and we're just
going to um talk to you about it and
have you asked the question that you
know really burning for you when it
comes to all of this stuff um and the
biggest thing really is
just understand that what most people
are doing what the mainstream is doing
so to say is
not um what you should be doing if you
have a goal as an entrepreneur
entrepreneurialism and especially the
successful
entrepreneurs are always very Contra
counterintuitive they're contrarians I
like to call myself a contrarian in a
lot of ways you know and that's the
reason why because I don't want to have
the results that everybody else has Y
and if I don't want the same results I
can't do the same things for you so you
need to keep on learning and need to
keep on going and looking for answers
and you will find the answers and that's
the number number one thing assume that
the answers are already out there and
you just have to find them that's
perfect to be a trend Setter you have to
be a part of communities you have to
participate in groups and the groups the
activities that you do within those
groups if they're great they
resonate and they then you you you are
the head of the trend that's how you
know when you participate
in and and you're part of certain groups
investor groups then you know what's
going to happen before it happens if
you're learning something in the news
you've already missed the boat all
should if you want to take that that
that that if you want to take the
journey into
entrepreneurialism um thinking about
giving is always going to produce
something in return for you but if
you're constantly taking taking taking
and spending money um you're going to
lose that essence of freed because
you're going to be you're going to be a
slave to your credit card you're going
to be a slave to your employer you're
not going to live a a fruitful life
because I didn't become an entrepreneur
because I wanted to be uh like I wanted
to be on a boat you know and hang out I
think those are byproducts and if it if
it happens it happens I I was an
entrepreneur because when my son was
born I said I want to be in every aspect
of his
life and I am mhm every aspect of his
life I want to be able to know I want to
be able to be there I want to have that
freedom because that love that I have
from him is endless it's the one thing
that I always do with you know um or did
with coaching
clients um the one thing that we always
did was to sit down and say imagine
right now that you're at the end of your
life what would give you the feeling my
life this life was worth
living and really think deeply of that
like put yourself anybody who's watching
this you know put yourself in that
situation really imagine that you on
your
Deathbat and what would you think in
that moment would have been worth living
for and I think that's
the most important part and that's a
part that a lot of people forget when
they get into
autopilot and they care more about Black
Friday than they care about everything
else makes you think folks so um today's
you know we changed the tone of this
hustle Zone because U Inside the Mind of
entrepreneurs is like yeah
entrepreneurialism is about about go go
go go go and get take action but
sometimes we need to take time to
reflect and that's why we've changed the
tone for tonight uh because we really
want you to think about your decisions
like this is not easy entrepreneurialism
is not easy the whole aspect of taking
risk you know you have to have a game
plan because you can get yourself caught
up real quick because you're doing
something that's greater than yourself
greater than what you can afford to take
on you know anytime you're creating
things for millions of of people you put
yourself at risk you know because
there's so many variables that you have
to take care of and um I'm going to
leave everyone tonight you know think
about Black Friday and how it makes you
feel and how emotional it makes you feel
you know and don't think don't be
impulsive just think about the way it
makes you feel and that should be
enough to to to ask yourself should I
buy if I feel this way
oh yeah welcome to
the hustle
[Laughter]
Zone
yeah yeah no doubt talk to you later
Archer there